<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>neural-networks-reading-group on Neural Networks Reading Group UoB</title>
    <link>/tags/neural-networks-reading-group/</link>
    <description>Recent content in neural-networks-reading-group on Neural Networks Reading Group UoB</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/neural-networks-reading-group/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Shooting Formulation of Deep Learning</title>
      <link>/a-shooting-formulation-of-deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/a-shooting-formulation-of-deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday the \(7^{\text{th}}\) of April, Anthony presented A Shooting Formulation of Deep Learning. This is closely related to Neural ODEs and Augmented Neural ODEs. The abstract is given below:
 A residual network may be regarded as a discretization of an ordinary differential equation (ODE) which, in the limit of time discretization, defines a continuous-depth network. Although important steps have been taken to realize the advantages of such continuous formulations, most current techniques assume identical layers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Neural Networks reading group website!</title>
      <link>/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone! I hope you are as excited as we are about the Neural Network reading group. We thought we’d make it more engaging by having a simple website where we can share links to the papers, post summaries and ideas. This is still a work in progress and feeback and suggestions are very much appreciated. For now, you can send your feedback to m.camaraescudero@bristol.ac.uk or to ys18223@bristol.ac.uk.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
