<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>variational autoencoder on Neural Networks Reading Group UoB</title>
    <link>https://neuralnetworksbristol.netlify.app/tags/variational-autoencoder/</link>
    <description>Recent content in variational autoencoder on Neural Networks Reading Group UoB</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://neuralnetworksbristol.netlify.app/tags/variational-autoencoder/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learning Latent Subspaces in Variational Autoencoders</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworksbristol.netlify.app/learning-latent-subspaces-in-variational-autoencoders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuralnetworksbristol.netlify.app/learning-latent-subspaces-in-variational-autoencoders/</guid>
      <description>On Monday \(9^{\text{th}}\) of November Pierre presented Learning Latent Subspaces in Variational Autoencoders by Klys et al. The slides are available here and the abstract is given below:
 Variational autoencoders (VAEs) [10, 20] are widely used deep generative models capable of learning unsupervised latent representations of data. Such representations are often difficult to interpret or control. We consider the problem of unsupervised learning of features correlated to specific labels in a dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adversarial Variational Bayes</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworksbristol.netlify.app/adversarial-variational-bayes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuralnetworksbristol.netlify.app/adversarial-variational-bayes/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday \(28^{\text{th}}\) of October Mauro presented Adversarial Variational Bayes by Mescheder et al. You can find the slides for the presentation here. The abstract is given below:
 Variational Autoencoders (VAEs) are expressive latent variable models that can be used to learn complex probability distributions from training data. However, the quality of the resulting model crucially relies on the expressiveness of the inference model. We introduce Adversarial Variational Bayes (AVB), a technique for training Variational Autoencoders with arbitrarily expressive inference models.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
