<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>deep-neural-network on Neural Networks Reading Group UoB</title>
    <link>https://neuralnetworksbristol.netlify.app/tags/deep-neural-network/</link>
    <description>Recent content in deep-neural-network on Neural Networks Reading Group UoB</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://neuralnetworksbristol.netlify.app/tags/deep-neural-network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Neural Word Embedding as Implicit Matrix Factorization</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworksbristol.netlify.app/neural-word-embedding-as-implicit-matrix-factorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuralnetworksbristol.netlify.app/neural-word-embedding-as-implicit-matrix-factorization/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday the \(10^{\text{th}}\) of February Patrick presented Neural Word Embedding as Implicit Matrix Factorization by Levy and Goldberg. You can find some hand-written notes here. The abstract is given below.
 We analyze skip-gram with negative-sampling (SGNS), a word embedding method introduced by Mikolov et al., and show that it is implicitly factorizing a word-context matrix, whose cells are the pointwise mutual information (PMI) of the respective word and context pairs, shifted by a global constant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Neural Networks reading group website!</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworksbristol.netlify.app/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neuralnetworksbristol.netlify.app/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone! I hope you are as excited as we are about the Neural Network reading group. We thought we’d make it more engaging by having a simple website where we can share links to the papers, post summaries and ideas. This is still a work in progress and feeback and suggestions are very much appreciated. For now, you can send your feedback to m.camaraescudero@bristol.ac.uk or to ys18223@bristol.ac.uk.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
