<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>neural-networks on Neural Networks Reading Group UoB</title>
    <link>/categories/neural-networks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in neural-networks on Neural Networks Reading Group UoB</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/neural-networks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Expectation Backpropagation: Parameter-Free Training of Multilayer Neural Networks with Continuous or Discrete Weights</title>
      <link>/expectation-backpropagation-parameter-free-training-of-multilayer-neural-networks-with-continuous-or-discrete-weights/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/expectation-backpropagation-parameter-free-training-of-multilayer-neural-networks-with-continuous-or-discrete-weights/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday \(14^{\text{th}}\) of April I presented Expectation Backpropagation:Parameter-Free Training of Multilayer Neural Networks with Continuous or Discrete Weights. The abstract is given below.
 Multilayer Neural Networks (MNNs) are commonly trained using gradient descent-based methods, such as BackPropagation (BP). Inference in probabilistic graphical models is often done using variational Bayes methods, such as Expectation Propagation (EP). We show how an EP based approach can also be used to train deterministic MNNs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partially Exchangeable Networks and Architectures for Learning Summary Statistics in Approximate Bayesian Computation</title>
      <link>/partially-exchangeable-networks-and-architectures-for-learning-summary-statistics-in-approximate-bayesian-computation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/partially-exchangeable-networks-and-architectures-for-learning-summary-statistics-in-approximate-bayesian-computation/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday 7\(^{\text{th}}\) of April Mark Beaumont presented Partially Exchangeable Networks and Architectures for Learning Summary Statistics in Approximate Bayesian Computation. The abstract is given below.
 We present a novel family of deep neural architectures, named partially exchangeable networks (PENs) that leverage probabilistic symmetries. By design, PENs are invariant to block-switch transformations, which characterize the partial exchangeability properties of conditionally Markovian processes. Moreover, we show that any block-switch invariant function has a PEN-like representation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uniform convergence may be unable to explain generalization in deep learning</title>
      <link>/uniform-convergence-may-be-unable-to-explain-generalization-in-deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/uniform-convergence-may-be-unable-to-explain-generalization-in-deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday 10\(^{\text{th}}\) of March Patrick Rubin-Delanchy presented the 2019 NeurIPS paper winner of the Outstanding New Directions Paper Award, titled “Uniform convergence may be unable to explain generalization in deep learning” by Vaishnavh Nagarajan and J. Zico Kolter.
The abstract is given below.
 Aimed at explaining the surprisingly good generalization behavior of overparameterized deep networks, recent works have developed a variety of generalization bounds for deep learning, all based on the fundamental learning-theoretic technique of uniform convergence.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>