<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>neural-networks on Neural Networks Reading Group UoB</title>
    <link>/categories/neural-networks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in neural-networks on Neural Networks Reading Group UoB</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/neural-networks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Train your Energy-Based Models </title>
      <link>/how-to-train-your-energy-based-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/how-to-train-your-energy-based-models/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday teh \(24^{\text{th}}\) of February Sam presented How to train your energy-based models by Yang Song and Diederik P. Kingma. You can find his presentation here and the abstract below.
 Energy-Based Models (EBMs), also known as non-normalized probabilistic models, specify probability density or mass functions up to an unknown normalizing constant. Unlike most other probabilistic models, EBMs do not place a restriction on the tractability of the normalizing constant, thus are more flexible to parameterize and can model a more expressive family of probability distributions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Word Embedding as Implicit Matrix Factorization</title>
      <link>/neural-word-embedding-as-implicit-matrix-factorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/neural-word-embedding-as-implicit-matrix-factorization/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday the \(10^{\text{th}}\) of February Patrick presented Neural Word Embedding as Implicit Matrix Factorization by Levy and Goldberg. You can find some hand-written notes here. The abstract is given below.
 We analyze skip-gram with negative-sampling (SGNS), a word embedding method introduced by Mikolov et al., and show that it is implicitly factorizing a word-context matrix, whose cells are the pointwise mutual information (PMI) of the respective word and context pairs, shifted by a global constant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep learning of contagion dynamics on complex networks</title>
      <link>/deep-learning-of-contagion-dynamics-on-complex-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/deep-learning-of-contagion-dynamics-on-complex-networks/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday \(3^{\text{th}}\) of February Sam Tickle presented Deep learning of contagion dynamics on complex networks. The slides are available here and the abstract is given below.
 Forecasting the evolution of contagion dynamics is still an open problem to which mechanistic models only offer a partial answer. To remain mathematically or computationally tractable, these models must rely on simplifying assumptions, thereby limiting the quantitative accuracy of their predictions and the complexity of the dynamics they can model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Tangent Kernel: Convergence and Generalization in Neural Networks</title>
      <link>/neural-tangent-kernel-convergence-and-generalization-in-neural-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/neural-tangent-kernel-convergence-and-generalization-in-neural-networks/</guid>
      <description>On Monday \(23^{\text{rd}}\) of November Mingxuan presented Neural Tangent Kernel: Convergence and Generalization in Neural Networks. You can find the abstract below:
 At initialization, artificial neural networks (ANNs) are equivalent to Gaussian processes in the infinite-width limit (16; 4; 7; 13; 6), thus connecting them to kernel methods. We prove that the evolution of an ANN during training can also be described by a kernel: during gradient descent on the parameters of an ANN, the network function fθ (which maps input vectors to output vectors) follows the kernel gradient of the functional cost (which is convex, in contrast to the parameter cost) w.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Inverse Problems with Invertible Neural Networks</title>
      <link>/analyzing-inverse-problems-with-invertible-neural-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/analyzing-inverse-problems-with-invertible-neural-networks/</guid>
      <description>On Monday \(16^{\text{th}}\) of November Mark presented Analyzing Inverse Problems with Invertible Neural Networks. You can find the abstract below:
 For many applications, in particular in natural science, the task is to determine hidden system parameters from a set of measurements. Often, the forward process from parameter- to measurement-space is well-defined, whereas the inverse problem is ambiguous: multiple parameter sets can result in the same measurement. To fully characterize this ambiguity, the full posterior parameter distribution, conditioned on an observed measurement, has to be determined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adversarial Variational Bayes</title>
      <link>/adversarial-variational-bayes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/adversarial-variational-bayes/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday \(28^{\text{th}}\) of October Mauro presented Adversarial Variational Bayes by Mescheder et al. You can find the slides for the presentation here. The abstract is given below:
 Variational Autoencoders (VAEs) are expressive latent variable models that can be used to learn complex probability distributions from training data. However, the quality of the resulting model crucially relies on the expressiveness of the inference model. We introduce Adversarial Variational Bayes (AVB), a technique for training Variational Autoencoders with arbitrarily expressive inference models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Processes</title>
      <link>/neural-processes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/neural-processes/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday \(14^{\text{th}}\) of July, Mingxuan presented Neural Processes and Conditional Neural Processes by Marta Garnelo et al. You can find the notes here.
Abstract for Neural Processes:
 A neural network (NN) is a parameterised function that can be tuned via gradient descent to approximate a labelled collection of data with high precision. A Gaussian process (GP), on the other hand, is a probabilistic model that defines a distribution over possible functions, and is updated in light of data via the rules of probabilistic inference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto-Encoding Variational Bayes</title>
      <link>/auto-encoding-variational-bayes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/auto-encoding-variational-bayes/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday \(7^{\text{th}}\) of July, Mauro Camara Escudero presented Auto-Encoding Variational Bayes. Slides can be found here. The abstract is given below.
 How can we perform efficient inference and learning in directed probabilistic models, in the presence of continuous latent variables with intractable posterior distributions, and large datasets? We introduce a stochastic variational inference and learning algorithm that scales to large datasets and, under some mild differentiability conditions, even works in the intractable case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mining gold from implicit models to improve likelihood-free inference</title>
      <link>/mining-gold-from-implicit-models-to-improve-likelihood-free-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/mining-gold-from-implicit-models-to-improve-likelihood-free-inference/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday \(30^{\text{th}}\) of June Mark Beaumont presented Mining gold from implicit models to improve likelihood-free inference by Johann Brehmer et al. The abstract is given below:
 Simulators often provide the best description of real-world phenomena. However, the probability density that they implicitly define is often intractable, leading to challenging inverse problems for inference. Recently, a number of techniques have been introduced in which a surrogate for the intractable density is learned, including normalizing flows and density ratio estimators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning for Multi-Scale Changepoint Detection in Multivariate Time Series</title>
      <link>/deep-learning-for-multi-scale-changepoint-detection-in-multivariate-time-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/deep-learning-for-multi-scale-changepoint-detection-in-multivariate-time-series/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday’s 5th of May Sam Tickle has presented Deep Learning for Multi-Scale Changepoint Detection in Multivariate Time Series. The abstract is given below.
 Many real-world time series, such as in health, have changepoints where the system’s structure or parameters change. Since changepoints can indicate critical events such as onset of illness, it is highly important to detect them. However, existing methods for changepoint detection (CPD) often require user-specified models and cannot recognize changes that occur gradually or at multiple time-scales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markov Chain Monte Carlo and Variational Inference: Bridging the Gap</title>
      <link>/markov-chain-monte-carlo-and-variational-inference-bridging-the-gap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/markov-chain-monte-carlo-and-variational-inference-bridging-the-gap/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday \(28^{\text{th}}\) of April Andi Wang presented Markov Chain Monte Carlo and Variational Inference: Bridging the Gap - Tim Salimans. His slides are available here and the abstract is given below.
 Recent advances in stochastic gradient variational inference have made it possible to perform variational Bayesian inference with posterior approximations containing auxiliary random variables. This enables us to explore a new synthesis of variational inference and Monte Carlo methods where we incorporate one or more steps of MCMC into our variational approximation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expectation Backpropagation: Parameter-Free Training of Multilayer Neural Networks with Continuous or Discrete Weights</title>
      <link>/expectation-backpropagation-parameter-free-training-of-multilayer-neural-networks-with-continuous-or-discrete-weights/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/expectation-backpropagation-parameter-free-training-of-multilayer-neural-networks-with-continuous-or-discrete-weights/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday \(14^{\text{th}}\) of April I presented Expectation Backpropagation:Parameter-Free Training of Multilayer Neural Networks with Continuous or Discrete Weights. The abstract is given below.
 Multilayer Neural Networks (MNNs) are commonly trained using gradient descent-based methods, such as BackPropagation (BP). Inference in probabilistic graphical models is often done using variational Bayes methods, such as Expectation Propagation (EP). We show how an EP based approach can also be used to train deterministic MNNs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partially Exchangeable Networks and Architectures for Learning Summary Statistics in Approximate Bayesian Computation</title>
      <link>/partially-exchangeable-networks-and-architectures-for-learning-summary-statistics-in-approximate-bayesian-computation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/partially-exchangeable-networks-and-architectures-for-learning-summary-statistics-in-approximate-bayesian-computation/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday 7\(^{\text{th}}\) of April Mark Beaumont presented Partially Exchangeable Networks and Architectures for Learning Summary Statistics in Approximate Bayesian Computation. The abstract is given below.
 We present a novel family of deep neural architectures, named partially exchangeable networks (PENs) that leverage probabilistic symmetries. By design, PENs are invariant to block-switch transformations, which characterize the partial exchangeability properties of conditionally Markovian processes. Moreover, we show that any block-switch invariant function has a PEN-like representation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uniform convergence may be unable to explain generalization in deep learning</title>
      <link>/uniform-convergence-may-be-unable-to-explain-generalization-in-deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/uniform-convergence-may-be-unable-to-explain-generalization-in-deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday 10\(^{\text{th}}\) of March Patrick Rubin-Delanchy presented the 2019 NeurIPS paper winner of the Outstanding New Directions Paper Award, titled “Uniform convergence may be unable to explain generalization in deep learning” by Vaishnavh Nagarajan and J. Zico Kolter.
The abstract is given below.
 Aimed at explaining the surprisingly good generalization behavior of overparameterized deep networks, recent works have developed a variety of generalization bounds for deep learning, all based on the fundamental learning-theoretic technique of uniform convergence.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>